citrixonline.com 2010-08-20

# Citrix Online: privacy policy

Last Updated: January 13, 2010

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.citrixonline.com](http://www.citrixonline.com/) and [www.workshifting.com](http://www.workshifting.com/), sites owned by Citrix Online, a division of Citrix Systems, Inc. Citrix Online is committed to respecting your privacy and complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union.

Citrix Online welcomes your feedback about this privacy policy. Send your questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement to [privacy@citrixonline.com](mailto:privacy@citrixonline.com).

**Contents**

  1. **What is Citrix Online? What is Workshifting?**
  2. **What information does Citrix Online gather/track and how is it used?**
  3. **With whom does Citrix Online share the information?**
  4. **How does Citrix Online protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?**
  5. **How does this privacy policy relate to the other Citrix Online product privacy policies such as GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting?**
  6. **Who can I contact if I have additional questions?**

**1\. What is Citrix Online? What is Workshifting?**

Citrix Online is the leading provider of Web-based remote-access, collaboration and customer-support technologies. Citrix Online's award-winning screen-sharing technology enables customers to work from anywhere with anyone – using our remote-connectivity tools to save time, get more done and connect to others around the world.

Workshifting ([www.workshifting.com](http://www.workshifting.com/)) is a blog sponsored by Citrix Online about Web commuting.

**2\. What information does Citrix Online gather/track and how is it used?**

All information gathered at either [www.citrixonline.com](http://www.citrixonline.com/) or on [www.workshifting.com](http://www.workshifting.com/) is done so on a voluntary basis. You need not provide us with any personal information to use these sites. Information submitted on these sites can include contact information such as email addresses, comments on blog postings and job and press inquiries.

TRAFFIC PATTERNS: We track aggregate traffic patterns throughout our sites, .however, we do not correlate this information with personally identifiable data about individual users. We also track domain names, browser types and MIME type.

COOKIES: A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. We use cookies to track user traffic patterns and hold certain registration information. When you register for services at Citrix Online sites, we use cookies to store unique, randomly assigned user IDs that we generate for administrative purposes. These cookies enable you to enter the Citrix Online sites without having to log on each time. We do not store passwords or any Personal Information about you in the cookies.

We continuously improve our Web sites and utilize different Web analytic tools to help us do so. We are interested in how visitors use our Web sites, what they like and dislike, and where they have problems. The Web beacons used in connection with our Web analytics services do not share any personally identifiable information about our Web site visitors with third parties. Our tools may gather data such as what browser a person uses, what operating systems are used and what content, products and services are reviewed when visiting or registering for services at one of our Web sites. This information is used solely to assist Citrix Online in maintaining more effective and useful Web sites for our customers.

Citrix Online also partners with selected marketing companies to help us track the effectiveness of our Web sites, generate visitor traffic and as part of our affiliate referral program through Commission Junction (http://www.cj.com). When a partner refers a visitor to us from any of these sites, they set a Web beacon and a cookie on our site. An ad ID and a partner ID are stored in the cookie, but no personally identifiable information specific to the actual visitor is stored. Citrix Online does not see the cookie; we only include the Web beacon on our page, which results in a request to the partner's servers from the customer browser. We have no control over their use of the cookie after it is placed on our site.

The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. You can still review the Web site if you choose to set your browser to refuse all cookies; however, you must enable cookies in order to establish an account and to download and install Citrix Online products.

SURVEYS: In addition to required member information, we may conduct surveys and ask users to volunteer demographic information to be used on an aggregate basis for internal market research, presentation to advertisers and joint research projects with outside companies involved in product development. We use such information to better focus our product and personalize the scope of services offered to each individual user. Such information will not be passed to third parties without your prior consent unless where required by applicable law.

This privacy policy is subject to change at the sole discretion of Citrix Online. When we modify the privacy policy, we will post the changes in a revised policy statement. You are responsible for regularly reviewing the Citrix Online privacy policy to obtain timely notice of such revisions.

**3\. With whom does Citrix Online share the information?**

Ensuring your privacy is important to us. We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties.

Citrix Online products and services by necessity require us to provide some customer information to third parties in order to conduct business. We may occasionally employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include processing credit card payments, sending postal mail and email, analyzing data and providing marketing assistance. They only have access to personal information needed to perform their functions and may not use it for any other purpose. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Also, in the event that Citrix Online or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets.

Except in the limited instances as stated above, we will never voluntarily share personally identifiable information with any third party without the user's express consent or unless compelled by applicable state and federal laws. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

Citrix Online does not control the practices of our affiliates. If you have questions about how affiliates use the information gathered when you link to them, please read their privacy policies.

**4\. How does Citrix Online protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?**

Citrix Online uses industry-standard protocols to safeguard the confidentiality of personally identifiable information, including secure sockets layer (SSL) encryption and firewalls. Nevertheless, we remind you that no security measure is perfect.

**5\. How does this privacy policy relate to the other Citrix Online privacy policies for products such as GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting?**

Citrix Online ([www.citrixonline.com](http://www.citrixonline.com/)) and Workshifting ([www.workshifting.com](http://www.workshifting.com/)) provide links to Citrix Online products such as GoToMyPC (www.gotomypc.com) and GoToMeeting (www.gotomeeting.com). Anytime you click one of these links and are transported, you should be aware that this privacy policy differs from those of Citrix Online's other products.

**6\. Who can I contact if I have additional questions?**

For additional inquiries about the privacy of your information, you can contact Citrix Online via email at [privacy@citrixonline.com](mailto:privacy@citrixonline.com), by calling +1-805-690-6400 or by writing to us via regular mail at: Citrix Online, 6500 Hollister Avenue, Goleta, CA 93117. To reach our Global Customer Support department, you may contact us at [support@citrixonline.com](mailto:support@citrixonline.com).
